<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='rfc2629.xslt' ?>
<?rfc strict="yes" ?>
<?rfc toc="no"?>
<!-- valentin.binotto -->
<!-- <?rfc tocdepth="4"?> -->

<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes" ?>
<?rfc compact="yes" ?>
<?rfc subcompact="no" ?>
<rfc submissionType="IETF" category="info" docName="draft-valentinbinotto-rootdomain-verify" ipr="trust200902">

  <front>
    <title abbrev="Verifying domain names">A method to declare domain names that are not a subdomain of the primary domain as trustworthy</title>
    <author fullname="Valentin Binotto" initials="V." surname="Binotto">
      <organization>V434 Project</organization>
      <address>
        <email>valentin@v434project.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="July" day="15"/>
    <area>Domain Name System</area>
    <workgroup></workgroup>
    <keyword>Internet Draft</keyword>
    <abstract>
	    <t>This document describes a method by which the owners/administrators of a specific domain name can declare other domain names, which are not subdomains of the primary domain but are used by the owners/administrators of the primary domain, as trusted by using TXT records in the DNS zone of the primary domain.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>


  <middle>
    <section anchor="introduction" title="Introduction">
	    <t>Internet infrastructure providers sometimes use different domain names that are not hierarchically related. This can make it unclear whether a domain name can be trusted because the infrastructure provider simply uses a second domain name for a part of his infrastructure or network, or if it is a maliciously registered domain name that aims to pretend legitimacy. When using subdomains, this problem does not arise because with a trusted parent domain name, it can be assumed that the corresponding subdomain is also legitimate and trustworthy.</t>
    </section>
    
    
    <section anchor="conventions-and-definitions" title="Conventions and Definitions">
      <t>The key words "<bcp14>MUST</bcp14>", "<bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14>", "<bcp14>REQUIRED</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHALL</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHALL
NOT</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHOULD</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHOULD NOT</bcp14>", "<bcp14>RECOMMENDED</bcp14>", "<bcp14>NOT RECOMMENDED</bcp14>",
"<bcp14>MAY</bcp14>", and "<bcp14>OPTIONAL</bcp14>" in this document are to be interpreted as
described in BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119"/> <xref target="RFC8174"/> when, and only when, they
appear in all capitals, as shown here.</t>
    </section>
     
     
    <section anchor="the-specification" title="The Specification">
	    <t>A TXT record (<xref target="RFC1035" />) MUST be created in the authoritative DNS zone under the subdomain "vroot" below the primary domain of an infrastructure provider. In this entry, in addition to the corresponding entries in the WHOIS database, the first name and last name of the root domain owner MUST be recorded in such a TXT record.
Both the first name and last name are written in lowercase and separated by a period.
    <sourcecode type="txt" markers="false"><![CDATA[
        vroot.valentin-43-44.org.    IN   TXT   "valentin.binotto"
]]></sourcecode>
In another TXT record, under the subdomain "vroot", MAY can be defined which other domain names are also used by the infrastructure provider. This enumeration does not include subdomains of the primary domain. The listed domain names SHOULD be defined as close to the domain-root as possible, which means that, for example, individual subdomains of "example.com" SHOULD NOT be listed if the security and trustworthiness of "example.com" itself and all its subdomains below can be guaranteed.</t> 

	    <sourcecode type="txt" markers="false"><![CDATA[
vroot.example.net.    IN   TXT   "example.com:example.org"
]]></sourcecode>
	    
</section>
   

   <section anchor="security-considerations" title="Security Considerations">
      <t>According to the author, no security considerations apply to this document.</t>
    </section>
    
    <section anchor="iana-considerations" title="IANA Considerations">
      <t>This document has no IANA actions.</t>
    </section>
    
    
   </middle>

   <back>
   	<references title="Normative References">

	<reference anchor="RFC2119" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc2119">
        <front>
          <title>Key words for use in RFCs to Indicate Requirement Levels</title>
          <author fullname="S. Bradner" initials="S." surname="Bradner">
            <organization/>
          </author>
          <date month="March" year="1997"/>
          <abstract>
            <t>In many standards track documents several words are used to signify the requirements in the specification.  These words are often capitalized. This document defines these words as they should be interpreted in IETF documents.  This document specifies an Internet Best Current Practices for the Internet Community, and requests discussion and suggestions for improvements.</t>
          </abstract>
        </front>
        <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="14"/>
        <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="2119"/>
        <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC2119"/>
      </reference>
	<reference anchor="RFC8174" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc8174">
        <front>
          <title>Ambiguity of Uppercase vs Lowercase in RFC 2119 Key Words</title>
          <author fullname="B. Leiba" initials="B." surname="Leiba">
            <organization/>
          </author>
          <date month="May" year="2017"/>
          <abstract>
            <t>RFC 2119 specifies common key words that may be used in protocol  specifications.  This document aims to reduce the ambiguity by clarifying that only UPPERCASE usage of the key words have the  defined special meanings.</t>
          </abstract>
        </front>
        <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="14"/>
        <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="8174"/>
        <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC8174"/>
      </reference>
		
	<reference anchor="RFC1464" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc1464">
        <front>
          <title>Using the Domain Name System To Store Arbitrary String Attributes</title>
          <author fullname="Rich Rosenbaum" initials="R." surname="Rosenbaum">
            <organization/>
          </author>
          <date month="May" year="1993"/>
          <abstract>
            <t>This paper describes a simple means to associate arbitrary string information (ASCII text) with attributes that have not been defined by the DNS. This memo defines an Experimental Protocol for the Internet community.</t>
          </abstract>
        </front>
      </reference>
		<reference anchor="RFC1035" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc1035">
        <front>
          <title>Domain names - implementation and specification</title>
          <author fullname="P. Mockapetris" initials="P." surname="Mockapetris">
            <organization/>
          </author>
          <date month="November" year="1987"/>
          <abstract>
            <t>This RFC is the revised specification of the protocol and format used in the implementation of the Domain Name System. It obsoletes RFC-883. This memo documents the details of the domain name client - server communication.</t>
          </abstract>
        </front>
      </reference>
	
    	</references>
    	
    	<section anchor="Acknowledgments" title="Acknowledgments">
	   <t></t>
   	</section>
  </back>

</rfc>

